good morning to all of you
yesterday's newspapers
disclosure that
the bar council of india
suspended 28 advocates of uttar pradesh
state uttar pradesh war council for
indulging in fake mv claims and also
crime center workman compensation act
this is not a news to you because
previously we discussed the team topic
when alabama high court directed or
formed a special investigation team
looking to the
so
false games
while disposing the case of shafiq hamad
safika
i told you so in slp number 11 10 by
so
these uh allah
to note that
about 300 crores worth of
compensation has to be paid
because of the fake and false coins 946
claims have been identified by the thai
so therefore they have to form a seat
you remember this is recording the mv
act please remember if somebody dies
according to 166 you have got
the claim
petition you can file the claim petition
before the so-called mv act claims
tribunal and of course if he is a
workman you can file a compensation
under workman compensation also act also
but there are so many misdeeds in this
aspect you may be knowing whenever any
accident takes place in certain
occasions the at law advocates reach the
deceived behavior family they give some
advance they say that we'll file the
case we will find the case we will get
the you will get the so called
compensation and out of it 10 15 20
percent you have to give
and i know some lawyers who take
advanced checks from the party of course
parties are also we cannot say they are
also not that genuine so when because
the amount will be deposited into the
fixed fixed deposit will be there into
the account of the decision family so
unless they agree to you it is difficult
to get the money from it therefore they
will take the advantage
and please remember it amounts to
maintenance and champion ta so which is
unethical according to the professional
ethics which i'm going to tell you in
the final year sixth semester
see it is unethical it comes under so i
will advocate sector madness and chop
but i will tell you later coming to the
present case what happened is
so people do like this the advocates do
like this ultimately they claim high
amounts because they will be nexus
with the doctors that medical officers
and with the other side advocate on some
time that is insurance companies so many
things will be there because uh the
courts will be pressurizing you
to go for no kadharat in so many cases
so every day national economy there's so
many accounts
there at that time
due to the pressure from the courts are
due to others extraneous circumstances
they will be coming to a sort of
compromise taking advantage of the same
now fake crimes have been fired
the high court
along with high court they found a seat
of course the seat
in 2017 it happened the seat sat on the
issue for about
four years now they could identify only
233 suspicious claims of various
insurance companies maybe i say la moda
tata aig so many oriental then national
insurance company all these people
combined together they are given the
complaint
[Music]
then the claims for 300 crores of course
they were rejected by various tribunals
also investigation in most cases are
pending so now
the matter has come before the honorable
supreme court of india on 1610 i believe
on 1611 on 1611 2021
they asked the bca chairperson shri
manon kumar vishal to be present and
they asked the action to be taken by the
bar council of india why
because the bar council of uttar pradesh
is not interested in giving the names of
the so-called advocates even though sit
has identified about 28 advocates
so sit has filed the cases against 28
educates and i think 55 are still
pending
55 cases 28 persons have been identified
and still so many persons have to be so
many advocates have to be traced so
since this is a serious issue the bar
council of india is directed by the
honorable supreme court of india to take
necessary action in this connection bar
council of india tried to assess the
names of the persons by the border
council of up but no action they are not
interested ultimately based since basing
on the affairs since the 28th advocates
have been figuring as accused in so many
cases their names have been taken the
bar council of india sumoto suspended
those advocates and directed the bar
council of uttar malaysia to conduct an
inquiry complete the same within three
months and come forward whether they are
liable for punishment intersection 35
the advocates are act or not
you may be knowing advocates act is
there to of course to give protection to
the advocates
to protect their interests but at the
same time to weed out the so-called
black sheep in the legal profession so
very serious issue very pathetic issue
but
please remember if any advocate
sees this video please remember who are
there to give protection or to give get
compensation to the victims should be
real victims not fake victims we have
seen him railway kiss also suppose if a
person dies normally advocate goes and
puts a ticket in his pocket then he
claim compensation because they will get
about seven lakhs or so so many
michele's activities are being taken
that should not be there don't do it
nothing uh don't do it because as an
elder i'm advising you it will
recuperate also i can tell you i or it
will
fly back to you on your family also it
may have effect so don't
put false claims before the
tribunal if it is genuine okay there
will be bills
there will be bills for the which and
everything yes you claim nobody will
object about the same definitely the
period family needs some solace yes you
can claim stating that he is the only
breadwinner of the family there is
nobody yes the court will accept but
don't get false games and you will be
caught and now these 28 educators they
have to face criminal cases and once it
is proved markets of india may suspend
them also very bad thing so please don't
do it right this is the case relating to
the arrest and
reading out of the 28 advocates for
filing fake insurance claims thank you